Now is the time for heroes.
Escape to Victory is a drama, war film directed by John Huston.
A group of POWs in a German prison camp during World War II play the German National Soccer
Team in this powerful film depicting the role of prisoners during wartime.
Captain Robert Hatch, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Captain John Colby, played by Michael Caine.
Major Karl von Steiner, played by Max von Sydow.
Cpl. Luis Fernandez, Brazil, played by Pelé.
Renée, played by Carole Laure.
Terry Brady, England, played by Bobby Moore.
Escape to Victory (or simply Victory) is a 1981 sports war film directed by John Huston
and starring Sylvester Stallone, Michael Caine, Max von Sydow and Pelé.
The film is about Allied prisoners of war who are interned in a German prison camp during the
Second World War who play an exhibition match of football against a German team.
The film received great attention upon its theatrical release, as it starred professional footballers Bobby Moore,
Osvaldo Ardiles, Kazimierz Deyna, Paul Van Himst, Mike Summerbee, Hallvar Thoresen, Werner Roth and Pelé.
Numerous Ipswich Town players were also in the film, including John Wark,
Russell Osman, Laurie Sivell, Robin Turner and Kevin O'Callaghan.
Other Ipswich Town players stood in for actors in the football scenes – Kevin
Beattie for Michael Caine, and Paul Cooper for Sylvester Stallone.
Yabo Yablonsky wrote the script and the film was entered into
the 12th Moscow International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of nazi, escape, sports, football (soccer).
The tone is emotional.